<u>Communication Skills Assignment - 2</u>

Submitted By - Sayam Kumar Roll No - S20180010158 UG 2, Section - B

Interview Questions -

Question 1. Introduce yourself.

Answer - I am a sophomore Computer Science undergraduate from Indian Institute Information Technology, Sri City. I am a continuous learner and believe in working hard. I love to explore nature and enjoy spending time with my family.

Question 2. What are your strengths?

Answer - I am a willing learner and also like working on real world problems. I do not hesitate to take tough challenges and try my level best to accomplish them within time. I prefer working in a peaceful environment.

Question 3. What are your weaknesses?

Answer - I get uncertain about wrapping up time bound tasks. So I refactor the timeline by getting feedback from seniors.

Question 4. Where do you see yourself five years from now?

Answer - I see myself as a Professional Machine Learning Engineer and Python Developer going deep into the exploration of massive datasets. Also, I do believe in continuous growth and prefer to see a better version of myself in terms of both technical and personal skills.

Question 5. Discuss your resume.

Answer - My Resume mostly contains a gist of my work history, the projects I have worked upon and the skills I have learned. I always work in the way of sharpening my skills for both personal and professional growth.

Question 6. What are your career goals?

Answer - To gain more experience of working with Machine Learning Projects and become technically more strong, are my career goals.

Question 7. What motivates you?

Answer - My zeal to solve real world problems and becoming a better version of myself, motivates me.

Question 8. Why are you looking for a new job?

Answer - I believe in continuous growth. At my previous job, I felt I was overburdening myself with a lot of work and realized my growth becoming stagnant. So, I opt for a change. That's why I am looking for a new job.

Question 9. What was your biggest failure?

Answer - I worked on a project about three months ago. The project was about taking continuous backups and sending those files to AWS Cloud. I completed the project and after rigorous testing, I handed the project to my client. On real time execution, there was a small bug in appropriately placing those files in AWS Cloud. That caused a lot of trouble and it wasted a lot of my time to debug and actually get the error fixed. That was the failure of Python Script but I corrected it.

Question 10. Discuss your educational background?

Answer - Right now, I am pursuing a Bachelor's in Computer Science Engineering from IIIT, Sri City. I am in my sophomore year. I have finished a couple of MOOCs to get myself familiar with Machine Learning as I see it as a perfect blend of Maths and Computer Science.

SAYAM KUMAR

Machine Learning Enthusiast

@ sayamkumar049@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/sayam049

+91-9815247310
pithub.com/Sayam753

Sri City, India

EXPERIENCE

Natural Language Processing Intern

Snapper

🛗 Jan 2020 - Present

Pune, India

- Working remotely as a team to build a text summarising app using NLP.
- Using Selenium for web scraping and building datasets.

Backend Developer

IOTA

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019

Sri City, India

- Collaborated with a team of 10 members to build Technical Event Website of our college.
- Designed backend interface using Django Rest as primary web framework.
- Integrated PayTM Merchant APIs for event registrations.

PROJECTS

Send To S3

- Written a python script to send backup files to AWS S3 bucket using Boto3.
- Searched the files within a given time interval along with regex.
- Implemented logging to collect errors and sent results via email using smtplib module.

Machine Learning Projects

Aug 2019 - Present

- Trained Logistic Regression Classifier on Titanic Dataset. Data prepossessing using Pandas.
- Implemented a Deep Neural Network from scratch in Numpy for Cat Classification Problem. Used Adam optimiser and Xavier initialisation for better accuracy.

Movie Rating Web App

🛗 Apr 2019 - May 2019

- Developed a Movie Rating Web App using Django Rest Framework. Used Postman to test and document APIs.
- Implemented JWT based Authentication, custom permissions, browsable API, throttling and filtering for better performance.
- Deployed at movierating.pythonanywhere.com

VR Puzzle Game

₩ Feb 2019 - Mar 2019

- Designed a Game in Unity Engine whose solutions are hidden in images.
- Implemented VR using Vuforia Augmented Reality Packages for Unity.
- Handled Authentication by Rest Client Packages, Backend Support through Firebase and Maintained top 5 leaderboard.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer Science Indian Institute of Information Technology

Coursework:

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Object Oriented Programming
- Discrete Mathematics
- Linear Algebra
- Database Management System
- Digital Logic Design

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Secured Silver Medal at International Mathematical Olympiad at District level.
- Winner of TechFest'17 and Inspire Science Quiz at Chandigarh University.

STRENGTHS



LANGUAGES

English Hindi Punjabi



CERTIFICATIONS

- Deep Learning Specialization | Coursera
- Google AI | Explore ML: Beginner's Track
- IBM: What is Data Science?
- Machine Learning

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Projects Team Member IOTA, IIIT Sri City

🛗 Sept 2019 - Present